Guide to the Yale University Divinity School Memorabilia Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Audio-Visual Materials, Series V; *NOTE: CDs of Convocation lectures are available for purchase from the Yale Divinity School Bookstore (http://www.yaledivinitybookstore.com/category/audio-and-lectures)
  - Video
    - Other lectures and events
      - Forum on Theological Inquiry, 1996 Apr 12; 1 (Box V-14, Item barcode 39002098995807)
        Seitz presenter; Childs presiding; Adams, Bartlett, Keck and Wolterstorff respondents
      - Forum on Theological Inquiry, 1996 Apr 26; 1 (Box V-14, Item barcode 39002098995815)
      - The Bible: A Universal Book; Laymen's National Bible Association, YDS Student Chapter, [n.d.]; 1 (Box V-14, Item barcode 39002098995823)
      - Memorial Service: Marvin H. Pope, 1997 Nov 5; 1 (Box V-14, Item barcode 39002098995831)
- Women at Yale Divinity School, Series VI
  - YDS Women's Center
    - Miscellaneous (Box VI-4)
  - YDS Women's History Project
    - History Project Proposal, 1990 (Box VI-2)
    - Study on women at the Divinity School, 1931-1954 (Box VI-2)
    - Allen, Thelma Diener (Class of 1934) (Box VI-2)
    - Barker, Ester T. (Student, 1934) (Box VI-2)
    - Bowdin, Charlotte McHose (Class of 1932) (Box VI-2)
    - Buehler, Bernice (Class of 1934) (Box VI-2)
    - Cross-Hansen, Jody Lynn (Class of 1982) (Box VI-2)
    - Farley, Margaret (Doctoral Student and Faculty) (Box VI-2)
    - Forsberg, Joan B. (Class of 1953; Faculty 1971-1993) (Box VI-2)
    - Fortune, Marie M. (Class of 1976) (Box VI-2)
    - Frazier, Elizabeth Hart (Class of 1940) (Box VI-2)
    - Frey, Rebecca (Class of 1973, 1974) (Box VI-2)
    - Hein, Jeanne Humphreys (Class of 1954) (Box VI-2)
    - Hooke, Ruth Ferguson (Class of 1956) (Box VI-2)
    - Inkpen, Priscilla G. (Class of 1976) (Box VI-2)
    - MacDougall, Detra (Staff 1963 - 2008) (Box VI-2)
    - Mattes, Eleanor Bustin (Class of 1941, 1942) (Box VI-2)
    - McGee, E. Lee (Class of 1969, Faculty) (Box VI-2)
    - Miho, Fumiye and Braulio (Nanine) Ana Ines (Class of 1953) (Box VI-2)
    - Minter, Elizabeth (Student, 1934) (Box VI-2)
    - Morris, Jean (Faculty spouse) (Box VI-2)
    - Mowry, Lucetta (Class of 1940) (Box VI-2)
    - Olivarius, Ann M. (Class of 1977-1978) (Box VI-2)
    - Pulley, Bernice Cosey (Class of 1955) (Box VI-2)
    - Rasmussen, Jean Miller (Class of 1974) (Box VI-2)
    - Russell, Letty (Faculty 1974-2001) (Box VI-2)
    - Smith, Winifred W. (Student, 1936) (Box VI-2)
    - Strain, Anne Price (Class of 1938) (Box VI-2)
    - Streeter, Ella-Jean (Class of 1944) (Box VI-2)
    - Tyson, Katherine B. (Class of 1979) (Box VI-2)
    - Ward, Constance Chandler (Class of 1961) (Box VI-2)
    - Ware, Agnes Highsmith (Class of 1940) (Box VI-2)
    - Waterman, Thelma (Class of 1978) (Box VI-2)
    - Wimer, Alice Godfrey (Student, 1945) (Box VI-2)
    - Wolfe, Kathi Diane (Class of 1978) (Box VI-2)
    - Audio-visual material, 1 (Box VI-3)
    - Binder - Women's History Project (Written transcripts of taped interviews) (Box VI-3)
    - Excerpts of interviews from Women's History Project (Box VI-3)
    - Mounted photographs - Detra MacDougall and Letty Russell (Box VI-3)
    - Audio cassettes of interviews with women: Barker, Buehler, Forsberg, Farley, Frazier, MacDougall, Mapes, Miho/Braulio, McGee, Minter, Russell, Smith, Strain (Box VI-3)
    - Reel visual tape - Women's Interseminary Conference, 1973 Feb 5 (Box VI-3)
    - Interviews on floppy disc (Box VI-3)
  - Topically arranged material
    - SHE - Information for women at Yale, 1972-1973 (Box VI-1)
    - Yale's Women Coordinating Council, 1972 (Box VI-1)
    - YDS Wives, 1970-1974, n.d. (Box VI-1)
      incl. Chairman Reports, 1970-1974 Faculty Speakers Series, 1972 Programs, 1970-1972 Welcome Kit, n.d.
    - Crescent Community, 1972-1975 (Box VI-1)
      incl. notes, meetings, minutes, "Crescent Comments"
    - "A Search for Livable Life Styles" (special speaker series), 1970-1971 (Box VI-1)
    - Class of 1940 - Women (Box VI-1)
    - Jubilee Celebration - 50 Years of Women, 1980 (?) (Box VI-1)
    - "Liberation of the Yale Divinity School Library Men's Room", 1980 (Box VI-1)
    - Reflection articles on women, 1972, 1976,1982 (Box VI-1)
      "Flowers for Ruth", 1990 "YDS Women's Re-Union", 1980
    - Sampling of YDS Women Pioneers, 2014 (Box VI-1)
    - Study on Women at the Divinity School, 1931-1951 (Box VI-1)
    - Team Ministry (Box VI-1)
    - Voice (A Women's Creative Journal), 1996 (Box VI-1)
    - Women's Interseminary Conference, 1977 (Box VI-1)
    - Women in Ministry (newspaper articles), 1970s (Box VI-1)
    - Yale and Women (Box VI-1)
    - YDS Women's Reunions, 1993, 1994, 2010 (Box VI-1)
      incl. Panel Discussion: "In Our Time: Women at YDS Before the '60s"
- Gay, Lesbian, Straight, Bisexual Coalition, Series VII
  - Historical Material
    - Partial chronology of Coalition Leaders (1984-2000); Coalition Events, Memorabilia, 1985-1990 (Box VII-1)
    - Coalition Events, Memorabilia, 1991-1992, 1992-1994, 1994-1996, 1996-1998, 1998-2000, n.d. (Box VII-1)
    - Student Reflections, 1996 (Box VII-1)
    - Student Papers, 1981, 1983, 1994-1996 (Box VII-1)
    - Dear Theo's, 1982-1996 (Box VII-1)
    - Faculty Papers, Memoranda, 1975-1996 (Box VII-1)
  - Collected Material
    - Bibliographies and Catalogues, 1982-1996, n.d. (Box VII-2)
    - Clippings, 1984-1992, n.d. (Box VII-2)
    - Pamphlets, Articles, 1978-1986, 1990-1996, n.d. (Box VII-2)
    - Related Organizations, 1983-1996, n.d. (Box VII-2)
    - Worship and Education Materials, 1984, 1988, n.d. (Box VII-2)
  - Audiovisual material
    - Video audio cassettes: GLSB Coalition History Project, 1996 Apr 28 (Box VII-3)
    - Audio Cassette: "God and Other Unanswerable Questions" (music) by Doug M. Shontz, Jr., 1996 (Box VII-3)
    - Posters (6 hand-decorated boards) depicting Coalition events from 4 decades; includes photographs celebrating same-sex marriages in Marquand Chapel, flyers, info, newsclippings, etc., 1980s-2000s (Box VII-3)
- Save the Quad, 1997-2003; Series VIII
  - Correspondence, 1997-2003 (Box VIII-1–VIII-3)
  - Foundation for the Preservation of Sterling Divinity Quadrangle (Box VIII-4)
  - Material collected by Norvin Hein and Kaye Betts (Box VIII-5–VIII-6)
  - Construction plans/reports (Box VIII-7)
    Binders of construction plans
  - Blueprints, 2001, 2006; 1 (Box VIII-OV2)
    Dean's House renovation, 2001 East buildings, 2006 SDQ Floor ploans Day Missions Room, architect's sketch Program distribution plans
  - Blueprints, 2006, 2008; 1 (Box VIII-OV3)
    SDQ: Marquand Balcony, Organ, 2006 SDQ: Southeast wing, 2008
  - Project materials, including Library adaptive re-use, 2001-2003; 1 (Box VIII-OV1)
- Marquand Chapel, 1952, 2000/01-present; Series IX; Programs relating to weekday worship services held in Marquand Chapel, special events holiday liturgy, Baccalaureate/Commencement worship, Alumni worship, etc. Arranged chronologically.
  - Marquand Chapel, 1952, 2000-2005 (Box IX-1)
  - Marquand Chapel, 2006 July - 2009 October (Box IX-2)
  - Marquand Chapel, 2010/11-present (Box IX-3)
- Institute of Sacred Music, Series X
  - General
    Ephemeral material, including programs, brochures, catalogs. At present, the ISM keeps a complete collection of material documenting all their programs, concerts, colloquia and other events. This series constitutes a small sampling of these.
    - ISM catalogs, 1999–2011 (Box X-1)
    - ISM brochures, 1999–2008 (Box X-1)
    - Studies in Sacred Music, 1994, 2001 (Box X-1)
    - Concert in honor of Henry J. M. Nouwen, 2000 Jan 22 (Box X-1)
      Presented by Grammy Award winners Eugene Friesen, Cello and Paul Halley, piano & pipe organ in Marquand Chapel.
    - New England Psalmody, 2000–2001 (Box X-1)
    - "Up With A Shout", 2001 (Box X-1)
    - "30 Years at Yale", 2004 (Box X-1)
    - "Rejoice! Cebrating the Musical Legacy of Robert Baker", 2005 (Box X-1)
    - Installation of Taylor Boody organ in Marquand, 2007 Jun (Box X-1)
    - St. John's Bible (gift of ISM to Divinity Library), 2012 May (Box X-1)
    - Hymn Festival, 2012- (Box X-1)
    - Rothko Symposium, 1989 Dec 1-3 (Box X-1)
  - Couturier Collection at Yale, 1993–1994
    This collection is no longer housed at Yale Divinity School, but at the Menil Center in Houston, TX. Material in this sub-series relates specifically to the events surrounding the acquisition & celebrations of the Fr. Marie Alain Couturier collection at Yale Divinity School.
    - Correspondence, 1993–1994; Incl. Mme. Francoise Causse, Tom Rogers, Ryan Granger, Dominique de Menil, Mme. Picq (Box X-2)
    - Publicity re opening, News clippings, press releases, brochure, booklet, planning, photos, audio/video tapes (Box X-1)
- Berkeley Divinity School, Series XI
  Ephemeral material relating to Berkeley Divinity School, a seminary of the Episcopal Church, which affiliated with Yale Divinity School in 1971. This material duplicates and/or will be integrated into the official archives of Berkeley Divinity School, YDSL RG 216.
  - Annand Program for Spiritual Growth, 1993–1996 (Box XI-1)
  - Miscellaneous programs, brochures, 1996–2013 (Box XI-1)